

# Virgel P. Magalso Male, Lot 33 Block 10 Corinthian Subdivision, Masulog Road, Basak, Lapu-lapu City 6015, Philippines. Mobile No.: (+63922) 2539333, E-mail Add.: virgel\_magalso@yahoo.com

Objective: Seek a fulfilling Sales and Marketing Management position that will allow me to contribute my

knowledge and skills acquired through my bachelors' education and more than fifteen years of solid work experience in the field of Marketing and Sales Managements' Best Practice likewise in business development.

Skills: + Marketing and Sales Management individual, corporate and key accounts.

- + Public Relation's and Promotion Conceptualization, Implementation and Management.
- + Pricing and Contract Negotiation, Forecasting, Project Evaluation and Policy Making.
- + Sales Force and Distribution Management, Asset Management, Credit Management.
- + Retail Service Business Marketing & Sales Management, B2B Promo, Branch Site Development.

# Work Experience:

+ 17+01+2013 - 15-01-2014	Area Sales & Site Development Manager VISMIN Great Image Services Corporation	
+ 23-04-2008 – 05-12-2012	Professional Sales Representative (with Promotion and Business Development function) Pacific Healthcare (Phils.), Inc.	
+ 15-09-2006 - 01-04-2008	Sale Representative/Account Receivable Representative Metro Drug, Inc.	
+ 17-11-2003 - 28-04-2006	Professional Consumer Sales Representative. Pinoy Central Distribution, Inc. – Lactovitale.	
+ 28-04-2003 - 30-07-2003	Professional Medical Representative. Laboratoires Fournier Philippines, Inc.	
+ 2003 – Licensed.	Authorized Accredited Card Sales Agent. Citibank NA – Through: Real Cards, Inc.	
+ 09-09-2002 - 16-12-2002	Product Specialist. PhilColors Steel Forming Corporation.	
+ 2001- 2002	Inter-Branch Marketing Consultant to management.  Davao Wyltelcom – Telecom shop – Chain of Stores.	
+ 01-03-1998 - 01-03-2001	Authorized Sales Representative/ Account Executive. Globe Telecom ( GMCR ), Inc. Through its distributor: S. Herrera Brothers, Inc.	

## Project Accomplishments and Citation:

17-01-13 to 15-01-2014

Great Image Services Corporation, Handles 5 VISMIN Branches and 4 branch managers, 15 staffs, Overall in-charge of the executive direction towards achieving KRA's in Sales, ECS (exceed customer satisfaction) HRM (Human Resource Management) as well In Business Development (Site and Cross Marketing Business to Business Tie-ups). Team Vismin is highest nationwide in terms of up sell and new business development in the just concluded Valentines, Graduation, Mother's & Father's Day, Christmas Promos.

23-04-2008 - 05-12-2012 Pacific Healthcare (Phils.), Inc. (Handles nine principal companies) - Visayas. Open up Visayas area (Central & western area and Mindanao for business expansion of PHI, able to established business relationships with key Cebu wholesaler accounts And other local drugstore Chains. Handles Promotion for medinova, Sales and Collection For Hirudoid Brand and was successful to re-launched it to the visayas market. Plan promotional & formulate marketing schemes for both Trade accounts & MD's. Manage the Rose Pharmacy, Inc. account nationwide for sales, collection and marketing plan implementation. Open and handle three sixty pharmacy - Central Visayas, Negros Grace Pharmacy - Western Visayas iloilo and Bacolod, Crown Pharmacy Negros Oriental able Develop sub distributors for PHI like Dalle Essential drug, Inc for Ferring and Medinova - Mandaue City, SCR Ventures Corporation for Teva Primary Care- Cebu City, DOH Pharmaceutical Distributor for Grifols - Dumaguete City, One Med Marketing for Eurodrug - Bacolod City, Eight Degrees Marketing and Lead Pathway Distributors, Inc for IPCA Central Visayas and I-Vaxx Marketing for IPCA Davao City.

15-09-2006 - 01-04-2008 Metro Drug (Phils), Inc. - Pharma 7 General Lines (Handles 62 Principals) - Cebu. Performs drugstore detailing on new & old products to drugstore owner & clerks to Help them better informed about it. Do Sales and collection function and was able To hit sales & collection target, able to clean up accounts receivable on the area and Achieved a daily sales outstanding of an average 30 days. Identify new opportunities

And open up new partner drugstores for MDI on the area.

17-11-2003 – 28-04-2006 Pinov Central Distribution, Inc. – Lactovitale.

Lead the implementation of Sales and Marketing Drive for Lactovitale Principal Product. Able to Open, Maintain and Develop Key Accounts (Pharmacy, Grocery & Other Channels ) In Davao City and Other areas in Mindanao Region.

28-04-2003 – 30-07-2003 Laboratoires Fournier Philippines, Inc.

Re-Open for Business and develop Areas in North and South Cotabato., Open new accounts and regain client confidence especially Key Pharmacy Accounts and Prescribing and Dispensing Medical Practitioners.

Project: "Fones for Free @ Wyltelcom Part 1, 2, 3.

Project Partner: Davao Wiltelcom.

Formulate, Implement and manage Post-Paid Sales Promo for the 3rd and 4th quarter of 2001 and 1st and 2nd quarter 2002. Achieved and Surpassed Sales Quota set by Globe Telecom, Inc. and its Distributor Junrex, Inc., Also Help formulate advertising Concepts for the company's Radio and News Paper Advertisement.

Globe Telecom (GMCR), Inc. - Sales Agent of the Year Award.

Davao Area – A Special Annual Citation Award given to outstanding individual Sales Agent for their efficient, effective and consistent sales performance and business development for the year covered.

2001-2002

2000

1999 Project : "CellCraze @ CellStation."

Project Partner: Cellstation, Inc.

Help Formulate, Plan, Design, Implement and Manage the Sales Promo for 3rd and 4th quarter of Achieved and Surpassed Post-Paid Sales quota standard set by Globe Telecom

Distributor Telechoice, Inc.

1998 Project: "Great Gifts to Go."

Project Partner: S. Herrera Brothers, Inc. – Telecoms Division.

Help in the sales implementation of this promo for 3rd and 4th quarter of 1998 for S. Herrera Bros., Inc. in Partnership with Globe Telecom – Mobile Communications Group.

### **Educational Attainment:**

2005 Master in Business Administration (MBA) – Major in Corporate Governance.

University of South Eastern Philippines – School of Government and Management.

2001 Bachelor of Science in Commerce Major in Marketing.

University of Mindanao, Bolton St., Davao City.

Achievements: S.Y. 1999-2000 Department Representative – Commerce

## Seminar and Trainings Attended:

21-08-2009 Life Insurance Finacial Education (LIFE) Program.

Conducted by: Manulife Philippines, Inc.

27-01-2006 Creative Selling.

Conducted by: Guthrie Jensen – Consultants to Management.

29-04-2003 The New Art of Pharmaceutical Selling to the Filipino Doctors.

Conducted by: Association of Pharmaceutical Trainers.

Added Skills: Computer Literate on Microsoft Windows Application, also posses a Professional Drivers License.

### Affiliations:

1999 Authorized Sales Agent.

Semicon Integrated Electronics, Inc.

2001 Authorized Sales Agent.

Mactelcom Corporation.

2006 Authorized Distributor.

Load X-Treme – Portal Innovations Corporation.

### Professional References:

Bernadeth B. Napenas Artemio "Archie "Yamane II Gilbert P. Gelacio COO Service Delivery and transistion General Manager

Rose Pharmacy and Transformation Country Lead Biosite Medical Instruments
16 Emilio Osmena Street, Computer Sciences Corporation Evel 22 C Ayala Tower One Juna Subdivision, Davao City

Telephone No.: (+6332) 2541491 Makati City, Philippines. 8000, Philippines.

Mobile No.: (+63920) 9543823 Mobile No.: (+63908) 887 4419. Tel. No.: (+6382) 2969485 Mobile No.: (+63917) 851 2007